## **Michael Drumm**

210 Beech Park, Easton road, Leixlip, Kildare.

michaeldrmm@gmail.com
Mobile Number: 083 064 9849

My LinkedIn Address

**My GitHub Account** 

**My Digital Resume** 

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

My name is Michael Drumm, I have a degree in Business Studies with a solid background in sales. Over the last few years I have been working in the recruitment industry. For over a year now I have been building a future for myself in Software Development through books and online courses. Since February 2021 I have been enrolled in a part-time Full Stack Development course with Code Institute and absolutely loving every moment of it.

I have experience in building responsive websites mobile-first using HTML5 with semantic elements, CSS3 and Bootstrap 4. I have experience coding in JavaScript to enhance website features and designs through my course projects. For personal and private projects under the guidance of books, I have built small real-time applications using Python. I've recently had practical exposure building a working website built with Flask, Heroku and MongoDB.

I see myself enjoying Frontend development right now as I enjoy working with website design and UX and I want to gain more experience using JavaScript and it's libraries but saying that I would never limit myself to one area of Software Development, I am always keen on learning new programming skills.

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Applications: Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook), Balsamiq
- Markup Languages: HTML5, CSS
- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, Bootstrap 4, JSON, APIs, Python
- **Frameworks:** Flask
- **Cloud Platform:** Heroku (Deployment)
- Database: MySQL and MongoDB
- Operating Systems: Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows Vista, Linux (Basic)
- Content Management Systems: SharePoint
- Customer Service Experience
- Reception and Administration Skills
- Languages: (Spanish Intermediate, Portuguese Beginner)

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

2021 - Present Google UX Designer - Online Learning, Ireland

Google UX Design - Certificate (Google Certified)

Modules: UX Research, Wireframe, Prototype, User Experience Design

Usability Testing, Mockup, Figma, Adobe XD

**2021 – Present** Full Stack Software Development - Code Institute

Diploma in Full-Stack Software Development EQF-5

Modules: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Flask, MongoDB

JSON, APIs, Django, MySQL, Postgres

December - 2014 TEFL Ireland - Dublin

Certificate in Teaching English as a Foreign Language

Modules: Teaching Methods, Classroom Planning,

Time Management, Behaviour Management

2007 - 2010 Business Studies - Dublin Business School

**Degree in Business Studies** 

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

May 2021 - Aug 2021 Cisco, (Remote) - Contract

Cisco develops, manufactures and sells networking hardware, software, telecommunications equipment and other high-technology services and products.

# **IT Recruitment Specialist**

- Writing and posting technical job descriptions.
- Sourcing potential candidates on niche platforms, like Stack Overflow and GitHub.
- Performing pre-screening calls to analyse applicants' abilities.
- Interviewing candidates combining various methods
- Coordinate with IT team leaders to forecast department goals and hiring needs.
- Craft and send personalized recruiting emails with current job openings to passive candidates.
- Handling the offer stage.

# Jul 2019 - Nov 2021 Mercury Engineering, Leixlip (Intel)

Mercury is an Electrical and Mechanical European contractor with large-scale projects across multiple sectors.

# **Recruitment Specialist**

- Principal Recruitment Specialist for the largest project in the history of Ireland on an 8- billion-euro project in Intel for a new Semiconductor Manufacturing Facility in Leixlip, Hospital project in Tallaght, The New Children's Hospital (NCH) in Rialto, Facebook Data Centre project in Clonee and a Pharmaceutical project in Dundalk.
- Direct dealings with all management on site: Mechanical and Electrical teams including Operations Managers, Contract Managers, Construction Managers, Assistant Construction Managers, Logistics Manager, Tool and Plant Manager, QA/QC Manager, H&S Sector Manager and H&S Trainer, Foremen, Doc Controllers, Package Leads and the Labor Coordinator.
- Weekly review of the recruitment plan with the Recruitment Manager, HR Business Partner and Project Director.
- Weekly meetings with the HR Manager on interviews and CV submittals, feedback from the Hiring Managers / Contract Managers and general updates on recruitment needs and concerns if any.
- Maintaining and updating of employee records on a shared drive containing letter of offers, contracts of employment, safe pass certificates, manual handling
- certificates, trade certs/cards and union membership details.
- Liaising with our visa agency (Newland and Chase) for costs and processes for candidates relocating from outside of the EU.
- Candidate relocation: Organization of PPS appointments, assistance and guidance of setting up of bank a/c's, organizing the booking of Safe Pass courses with partner training centers, accommodation assistance and the booking of security and start/induction dates on site.
- Execute the complete life cycle of the recruitment process, from identifying the candidates, the screening of CVS from agencies, direct sourcing and internal referrals, agency face to face meetings for recruitment needs and review of the recruitment plan.

- Preparing and managing multiple job roles from within Talent manager Mercury's internal database, publishing and editing jobs for Intel's and other projects mentioned according to the hiring plan. My responsibility was to ensure that each job advertisement is updated, attractive and categorized to the right business sector and project leader, me. Unpublishing advertisements if filled or if the positions were on hold for unexpected reasons.
- Using Indeed to advertise key roles
  maximizing exposure and interest in our
  recruitment needs. Managing the applications
  through indeeds job application portal,
  shortlisting through the portal and making
  accurate hires.
- Client management Working with recruitment agencies, providing them with regular communication with the information they need to target the ideal
- candidates for the roles we are recruiting for.
   Weekly face to face meetings on recruitment reviews.
- Providing an excellent candidate experience no matter the outcome of their application. Updating and maintaining information of candidate and client details such as phone numbers, email addresses, personal information, T & C's and main point of contact for each agency in the database.
- Candidate management in both the progressing and regretting of the application process.
- Attending recruitment drives to create awareness of the company's recruitment needs across Ireland in participation with registration and walk-in interviews.

# Aug 2018 - Apr 2019 Sigmar Recruitment, Dublin 2

Industry experts in recruitment across Ireland and Europe

### **Recruitment Consultant**

- Execute the complete life cycle of the recruitment process, from identifying the candidates, the screening by phone, candidate face to face meeting for interview preparation and follow-ups.
- Preparing and managing multiple job roles from within Arithon an internal database, publishing and

editing client jobs on websites such as Indeed, IrishJobs, Monster and Careerstructure using Yourecruit. My responsibility was to ensure that each post is updated, attractive and if filled removed.

- Providing excellent customer service to both clients and candidates. Updating and maintaining information of clients and candidates' details such as phone numbers, email addresses, T & C's and main point of contact for each company in the database.
- Using all available resources to search for candidates such as the internal database and websites like Indeed, IrishJobs, Monster and Careerstructure by filtering or Boolean strings and using initiative to generate more candidates.
- Building relationships with clients and candidates.
- CV screening and formatting.
- Meeting candidates for interview preparation.

## Jun 2017 - Jun 2018 Skillspot, Murcia (Spain)

Start-up recruitment company specializing in recruiting for the IT sector

#### **IT Recruitment Consultant**

- Execute the complete life cycle of the recruitment process, from identifying the candidates, the screening by phone and the follow-ups. Preparation of ads for recruiting websites.
- Advertising of vacancies on several work sites and daily update of candidates through advertising, search and network selection curriculums, selection of candidates to interview and evaluate the candidates for our client profile.
- Providing excellent customer service to clients and candidates. Updating and maintaining information of clients and candidates in the database. Using all available resources to search for candidates such as an internal database, Internet sites, cold calling and various recruitment practices.
- Worked closely with management / clients to fully understand the position requirements, negotiations and understand the fluctuations of market rates. Organization of interviews and preparation of candidates for interviews.
- Roles recruited for: Frontend and Backend Developers, Full Stack Developers, UX UI Design, .Net Developers, Java Developer, JavaScript Developer, PHP Developer etc.

## Sep 2015 - May 2017 Speak Your Mind, Murcia (Spain)

English teaching academy

#### **English Teacher**

- Taught English to all age groups, from children, teenagers and adults.
- Followed the Speak Your Mind curriculum.
- Worked with classes B1-B2-C1 using the Cambridge method (Reading, Speaking and Listening).
- Cambridge exam preparation, intensive studies.
- Took part in the mock exams. (Preparation of exams and grading completed exams).

# Sep 2014 - May 2015 Native English Academy, Murcia (Spain)

English teaching academy

### **English Teacher**

- Taught English to all age groups, from children, teenagers and adults.
- Worked with classes B1-B2 using the Cambridge method (Reading, Speaking and Listening).
- Cambridge exam preparation, intensive studies.
- Took part in the mock exams. (Preparation of exams and grading completed exams).

# Jul 2011 - Jan 2014 Vodafone, Dublin

#### Sales Agent

- Passionate in selling mobile phones, a range of wireless products, home landline, fixed broadband and car and different types of accessories.
- Providing existing and new customers with quality customer service.
- Built a strong rapport with all new and returning customers.
- Meet and exceed a quota for sales for individual and overall store targets.

- Assisting customers in troubleshooting their products and instructing customers on their proper use.
- Attention to detail at all times especially when dealing with cash and contracts.
- Dealing with difficult customers and attempting to mediate a satisfactory conclusion and handling volatile situations.
- Extensive experience in Microsoft Office programs including but not limited to: Outlook Express, Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Adobe acrobat and others.

# Sep 2007 - Sep 2010 Lidl, Leixlip

#### Sales assistant to Deputy Manager

- Training and development, performance management, planning and providing tasks, planning rosters for staff 3 weeks in advance.
- Store operations: management of profits and loss, facility management, safety and security, loss prevention and cost cutting and most importantly hitting store targets on a monthly basis.
- Product management: ordering, receiving, price changes, handling damaged products, stock orientation and ensuring 100% availability of all products for customers, opening and closing the store and dealing with staff issues that may arise.
- Problem solving under a constant pressure on busy peaks.
- Liaising with Store manager and District manager
- Maintaining excellent customer service, interaction and assistance, Customer is key.

## **REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST**